[
  {
    "topic_id": 1,
    "uuid": "f092196d-4ab9-43fd-8135-9fba43b8d96a",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'British voters decided to leave the European Union (Brexit), with 52% voting to leave.'?",
    "option_A": "Prime Minister David Cameron pledged a referendum on EU membership in 2013 if his Conservative Party won the next election.",
    "option_B": "The information provided is insufficient to determine the cause.",
    "option_C": "Cameron's attempt to renegotiate the U.K.'s EU membership terms failed.",
    "option_D": "The United Kingdom held a referendum on whether to leave or remain in the European Union on June 23.",
    "golden_answer": "A,C,D"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 1,
    "uuid": "429ced0e-c587-488b-866c-fac884890ad3",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'Global markets plummeted, and the British pound plunged following the Brexit vote.'?",
    "option_A": "The information provided is insufficient to determine the cause.",
    "option_B": "Prime Minister David Cameron pledged a referendum on EU membership in 2013 if his Conservative Party won the next election.",
    "option_C": "Cameron's attempt to renegotiate the U.K.'s EU membership terms failed.",
    "option_D": "The United Kingdom held a referendum on whether to leave or remain in the European Union on June 23.",
    "golden_answer": "B,D"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 1,
    "uuid": "d96866bc-a527-4d92-a83f-528c2a465f77",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'Scotland voted to remain in the EU (62% to 38%), diverging from the rest of the UK.'?",
    "option_A": "The information provided is insufficient to determine the cause.",
    "option_B": "Prime Minister David Cameron pledged a referendum on EU membership in 2013 if his Conservative Party won the next election.",
    "option_C": "The United Kingdom held a referendum on whether to leave or remain in the European Union on June 23.",
    "option_D": "British voters decided to leave the European Union (Brexit), with 52% voting to leave.",
    "golden_answer": "B,C"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 1,
    "uuid": "161e91de-74f2-4cec-b519-096efca25d04",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'Sinn Fein called for a referendum on unification with Ireland.'?",
    "option_A": "Prime Minister David Cameron pledged a referendum on EU membership in 2013 if his Conservative Party won the next election.",
    "option_B": "The information provided is insufficient to determine the cause.",
    "option_C": "British voters decided to leave the European Union (Brexit), with 52% voting to leave.",
    "option_D": "The United Kingdom held a referendum on whether to leave or remain in the European Union on June 23.",
    "golden_answer": "A,C,D"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 1,
    "uuid": "302a298d-9210-4f7b-848c-47c6e0139e86",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'Nigel Farage admitted a key Leave campaign promise about redirecting EU funds to the national health system was inaccurate.'?",
    "option_A": "The United Kingdom held a referendum on whether to leave or remain in the European Union on June 23.",
    "option_B": "The information provided is insufficient to determine the cause.",
    "option_C": "British voters decided to leave the European Union (Brexit), with 52% voting to leave.",
    "option_D": "Prime Minister David Cameron announced his resignation.",
    "golden_answer": "A,C"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 1,
    "uuid": "9af08038-080b-4fbe-975a-20e741462d0c",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'Brexit may encourage violent republican dissidents in Northern Ireland.'?",
    "option_A": "The United Kingdom held a referendum on whether to leave or remain in the European Union on June 23.",
    "option_B": "The information provided is insufficient to determine the cause.",
    "option_C": "British voters decided to leave the European Union (Brexit), with 52% voting to leave.",
    "option_D": "Prime Minister David Cameron announced his resignation.",
    "golden_answer": "A,C"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 2,
    "uuid": "bd8ac653-f13c-43ab-8d5e-c358176d44cd",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'COVID-19 pandemic: Caused lockdowns, terrified citizens, and triggered a financial meltdown, demanding immediate response and long-term planning.'?",
    "option_A": "WHO was notified of unusual pneumonia cases in Wuhan City, China on Dec. 31.",
    "option_B": "SARS-CoV-2 virus spread globally, causing infections and deaths.",
    "option_C": "Chinese authorities identified SARS-CoV-2 as the cause of the pneumonia cases approximately a week after the WHO notification.",
    "option_D": "The information provided is insufficient to determine the cause.",
    "golden_answer": "A,B,C"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 2,
    "uuid": "b6e93678-46f0-4410-9314-e58d32a65b3c",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'Some US state governments (e.g., Washington, Ohio, California, New York) developed testing, collaborated with health officials, and implemented social distancing and hospital preparation.'?",
    "option_A": "SARS-CoV-2 virus spread globally, causing infections and deaths.",
    "option_B": "WHO declared COVID-19 a pandemic on March 11, 2020, impacting global health and humanitarian efforts.",
    "option_C": "Experts advocated for systemic economic transformation, linking planetary crises like deforestation and climate change to increased pandemic risk and calling for investment in green infrastructure.",
    "option_D": "WHO was notified of unusual pneumonia cases in Wuhan City, China on Dec. 31.",
    "golden_answer": "A,B,D"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 2,
    "uuid": "965a948d-e385-4222-a1f5-f1be3cd5fe19",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'Governments worldwide began using the coronavirus crisis as a pretext to restrict fundamental freedoms, such as banning gatherings and censoring online content.'?",
    "option_A": "The information provided is insufficient to determine the cause.",
    "option_B": "Chinese authorities identified SARS-CoV-2 as the cause of the pneumonia cases approximately a week after the WHO notification.",
    "option_C": "Businesses laid off workers, households struggled with food, and international investment fled emerging markets, leading to widespread economic hardship.",
    "option_D": "WHO was notified of unusual pneumonia cases in Wuhan City, China on Dec. 31.",
    "golden_answer": "B,D"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 2,
    "uuid": "9e8b2a52-83b5-4758-a235-a9f051222a52",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'The pandemic increased suicide risk due to social distancing and economic fallout, challenging mental health care access.'?",
    "option_A": "WHO was notified of unusual pneumonia cases in Wuhan City, China on Dec. 31.",
    "option_B": "SARS-CoV-2 virus spread globally, causing infections and deaths.",
    "option_C": "The information provided is insufficient to determine the cause.",
    "option_D": "Trump administration failed to mobilize for COVID-19 despite warnings.",
    "golden_answer": "A,B"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 2,
    "uuid": "a6e5dcf1-3036-4261-9759-5f99fc88fecd",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'COVID-19 outbreak is overwhelming healthcare systems and disproportionately impacting vulnerable populations, including refugees, asylum seekers, and IDPs.'?",
    "option_A": "Governments worldwide began using the coronavirus crisis as a pretext to restrict fundamental freedoms, such as banning gatherings and censoring online content.",
    "option_B": "The information provided is insufficient to determine the cause.",
    "option_C": "WHO was notified of unusual pneumonia cases in Wuhan City, China on Dec. 31.",
    "option_D": "Chinese authorities identified SARS-CoV-2 as the cause of the pneumonia cases approximately a week after the WHO notification.",
    "golden_answer": "C,D"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 2,
    "uuid": "77875ec7-f05a-48fd-adb8-b9092a4597b4",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'Border closures and travel restrictions implemented by countries globally are disrupting humanitarian aid delivery and preventing the movement of asylum seekers and refugees.'?",
    "option_A": "Some US state governments (e.g., Washington, Ohio, California, New York) developed testing, collaborated with health officials, and implemented social distancing and hospital preparation.",
    "option_B": "The information provided is insufficient to determine the cause.",
    "option_C": "SARS-CoV-2 virus spread globally, causing infections and deaths.",
    "option_D": "WHO was notified of unusual pneumonia cases in Wuhan City, China on Dec. 31.",
    "golden_answer": "C,D"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 2,
    "uuid": "b99d6eaf-8814-4a2e-9416-c18b4f777f39",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'Lockdowns led to increased domestic violence, hunger, and suicide (victims, abusers, economically vulnerable populations).'?",
    "option_A": "The information provided is insufficient to determine the cause.",
    "option_B": "WHO declared COVID-19 a pandemic on March 11, 2020, impacting global health and humanitarian efforts.",
    "option_C": "SARS-CoV-2 virus spread globally, causing infections and deaths.",
    "option_D": "WHO was notified of unusual pneumonia cases in Wuhan City, China on Dec. 31.",
    "golden_answer": "B,C,D"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 2,
    "uuid": "9e242e40-154c-40fc-a6bf-4c0e575c80b2",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'Healthcare system strain caused reduced services for other conditions and subsequent deaths (healthcare system, patients with non-COVID conditions).'?",
    "option_A": "The information provided is insufficient to determine the cause.",
    "option_B": "Chinese authorities identified SARS-CoV-2 as the cause of the pneumonia cases approximately a week after the WHO notification.",
    "option_C": "WHO was notified of unusual pneumonia cases in Wuhan City, China on Dec. 31.",
    "option_D": "Some US state governments (e.g., Washington, Ohio, California, New York) developed testing, collaborated with health officials, and implemented social distancing and hospital preparation.",
    "golden_answer": "B,C"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 2,
    "uuid": "a911006c-42d3-49a6-acee-7a214610aff8",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'COVID-19 pandemic caused over 3.24 million deaths by May 6, 2021 (SARS-CoV-2 infections).'?",
    "option_A": "WHO was notified of unusual pneumonia cases in Wuhan City, China on Dec. 31.",
    "option_B": "The pandemic increased suicide risk due to social distancing and economic fallout, challenging mental health care access.",
    "option_C": "SARS-CoV-2 virus spread globally, causing infections and deaths.",
    "option_D": "Chinese authorities identified SARS-CoV-2 as the cause of the pneumonia cases approximately a week after the WHO notification.",
    "golden_answer": "A,C,D"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 3,
    "uuid": "afd3cba9-92bc-49be-a271-b32264004b76",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'The House and Senate recessed, the Capitol was locked down, and lawmakers were evacuated due to the breach.'?",
    "option_A": "Trump supporters stormed the U.S. Capitol, clashing with police, breaching security barriers, and forcing entry.",
    "option_B": "The information provided is insufficient to determine the cause.",
    "option_C": "Trump addressed supporters in Washington, D.C., urging them to protest the election results and march to the Capitol.",
    "option_D": "A joint session of Congress convened to certify the Electoral College vote.",
    "golden_answer": "A,C,D"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 3,
    "uuid": "0d9f819a-9fac-4d33-9876-b70e2984c24b",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'A woman was shot inside the Capitol by Capitol Police and later died.'?",
    "option_A": "Trump supporters stormed the U.S. Capitol, clashing with police, breaching security barriers, and forcing entry.",
    "option_B": "The information provided is insufficient to determine the cause.",
    "option_C": "Trump addressed supporters in Washington, D.C., urging them to protest the election results and march to the Capitol.",
    "option_D": "A joint session of Congress convened to certify the Electoral College vote.",
    "golden_answer": "A,C"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 3,
    "uuid": "a5fdfb08-9f0b-4721-97d9-39f3e44f86fd",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'Law enforcement cleared the mob from the Capitol.'?",
    "option_A": "The House and Senate recessed, the Capitol was locked down, and lawmakers were evacuated due to the breach.",
    "option_B": "Trump addressed supporters in Washington, D.C., urging them to protest the election results and march to the Capitol.",
    "option_C": "The information provided is insufficient to determine the cause.",
    "option_D": "Trump supporters stormed the U.S. Capitol, clashing with police, breaching security barriers, and forcing entry.",
    "golden_answer": "A,B,D"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 3,
    "uuid": "e3bd15cb-389e-47db-b949-5360b19e049e",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'After the Capitol was secured, Congress reconvened to continue the certification of President-elect Joe Biden's win.'?",
    "option_A": "A woman was shot inside the Capitol by Capitol Police and later died.",
    "option_B": "Trump addressed supporters in Washington, D.C., urging them to protest the election results and march to the Capitol.",
    "option_C": "The information provided is insufficient to determine the cause.",
    "option_D": "A joint session of Congress convened to certify the Electoral College vote.",
    "golden_answer": "B,D"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 3,
    "uuid": "982d19d4-3c4f-4a77-8e0b-bfce441c1e1b",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'Capitol Police Chief Steven Sund, House Sergeant at Arms Paul Irving, and Senate Sergeant at Arms Michael Stenger resigned.'?",
    "option_A": "The information provided is insufficient to determine the cause.",
    "option_B": "A joint session of Congress convened to certify the Electoral College vote.",
    "option_C": "Trump addressed supporters in Washington, D.C., urging them to protest the election results and march to the Capitol.",
    "option_D": "Nancy Pelosi and Charles Schumer called for Trump's removal from office.",
    "golden_answer": "B,C"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 4,
    "uuid": "95689e66-d0a2-4c80-b62a-94c073160a63",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'Abe outlined his vision for a 'free and open Indo-Pacific' in 2016.'?",
    "option_A": "Abe reinterpreted Japan's constitution in 2014, enabling military operations overseas.",
    "option_B": "The information provided is insufficient to determine the cause.",
    "option_C": "Increased diplomacy between Japan and Israel, starting with Benjamin Netanyahu's visit to Tokyo in 2014.",
    "option_D": "Abe returned to office as prime minister in 2012.",
    "golden_answer": "A,D"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 4,
    "uuid": "2b8e23ec-4b4c-4614-b651-c721bbb695ce",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'Abe promoted the Quadrilateral Security Dialogue (Quad) between Japan, India, the US, and Australia.'?",
    "option_A": "Abe returned to office as prime minister in 2012.",
    "option_B": "The information provided is insufficient to determine the cause.",
    "option_C": "Abe became prime minister of Japan in 2006.",
    "option_D": "Increased diplomacy between Japan and Israel, starting with Benjamin Netanyahu's visit to Tokyo in 2014.",
    "golden_answer": "A,C"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 4,
    "uuid": "bb7ae11e-cfbf-49e9-82a3-592c193a0fac",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'Security officers detained Tetsuya Yamagami and seized his handmade gun.'?",
    "option_A": "Shinzo Abe was murdered while campaigning in Nara on July 8, 2022.",
    "option_B": "Tetsuya Yamagami fired two shots at Shinzo Abe, hitting his chest and neck.",
    "option_C": "Shinzo Abe collapsed; Shinzo Abe; Bleeding from neck and chest after being shot.",
    "option_D": "Abe returned to office as prime minister in 2012.",
    "golden_answer": "A,B,C"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 4,
    "uuid": "b8f6c092-0629-445e-983c-0d07516e3800",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'Shinzo Abe was pronounced dead; Shinzo Abe; Hospital, 5:03 p.m., due to excessive bleeding.'?",
    "option_A": "The information provided is insufficient to determine the cause.",
    "option_B": "Tetsuya Yamagami fired two shots at Shinzo Abe, hitting his chest and neck.",
    "option_C": "Shinzo Abe was murdered while campaigning in Nara on July 8, 2022.",
    "option_D": "Abe promoted the Quadrilateral Security Dialogue (Quad) between Japan, India, the US, and Australia.",
    "golden_answer": "B,C"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 4,
    "uuid": "cc8c8f1a-fa76-48e3-820f-cd07fcafef2d",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'Seizure: Police seized the handmade gun used in the shooting, along with several others, from the shooter's home.'?",
    "option_A": "Shinzo Abe collapsed; Shinzo Abe; Bleeding from neck and chest after being shot.",
    "option_B": "Tetsuya Yamagami fired two shots at Shinzo Abe, hitting his chest and neck.",
    "option_C": "Shinzo Abe was murdered while campaigning in Nara on July 8, 2022.",
    "option_D": "The information provided is insufficient to determine the cause.",
    "golden_answer": "A,B,C"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 5,
    "uuid": "b01a77ed-6014-44cb-965a-1c0b069f5222",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'Elon Musk fired Twitter CEO Parag Agrawal, CFO Ned Segal, and general counsel Vijaya Gadde.'?",
    "option_A": "Elon Musk to acquire Twitter for $44 billion",
    "option_B": "Elon Musk acquired Twitter for $44 billion.",
    "option_C": "Trading in Twitter shares was suspended on the New York Stock Exchange.",
    "option_D": "The information provided is insufficient to determine the cause.",
    "golden_answer": "A,B"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 5,
    "uuid": "b3d1ddd8-e754-4c68-876c-7ff990e6bc63",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'Elon Musk implemented staff reductions at Twitter, including firing top executives and laying off a large portion of employees (post-October).'?",
    "option_A": "The information provided is insufficient to determine the cause.",
    "option_B": "Trading in Twitter shares was suspended on the New York Stock Exchange.",
    "option_C": "Elon Musk to acquire Twitter for $44 billion",
    "option_D": "Elon Musk acquired Twitter for $44 billion.",
    "golden_answer": "C,D"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 5,
    "uuid": "29b11640-bdf8-4827-aa7a-634fa9c46fb7",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'Elon Musk reinstated previously suspended accounts, including Donald Trump's, under a 'general amnesty'.'?",
    "option_A": "Elon Musk acquired Twitter for $44 billion.",
    "option_B": "The information provided is insufficient to determine the cause.",
    "option_C": "Elon Musk to acquire Twitter for $44 billion",
    "option_D": "Elon Musk implemented staff reductions at Twitter, including firing top executives and laying off a large portion of employees (post-October).",
    "golden_answer": "A,C"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 5,
    "uuid": "20ca1ca6-2cd8-4b0d-bf6e-8b9dfe456edf",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'Advertisers expressed concerns about brand safety and content moderation on Twitter under Elon Musk's ownership.'?",
    "option_A": "Elon Musk fired Twitter CEO Parag Agrawal, CFO Ned Segal, and general counsel Vijaya Gadde.",
    "option_B": "Elon Musk acquired Twitter for $44 billion.",
    "option_C": "Trading in Twitter shares was suspended on the New York Stock Exchange.",
    "option_D": "Elon Musk to acquire Twitter for $44 billion",
    "golden_answer": "A,B,D"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 5,
    "uuid": "bb64fc09-6411-473b-a3bb-ba607f141c01",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'General Motors suspended advertising on Twitter due to uncertainty about the platform's direction.'?",
    "option_A": "Elon Musk acquired Twitter for $44 billion.",
    "option_B": "The information provided is insufficient to determine the cause.",
    "option_C": "Elon Musk to acquire Twitter for $44 billion",
    "option_D": "Trading in Twitter shares was suspended on the New York Stock Exchange.",
    "golden_answer": "A,C"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 5,
    "uuid": "4cc14a39-a1d4-4b18-9c2e-a4dd3e8a1546",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'Elon Musk confirmed stepping down as CEO of Twitter once a replacement is found, transitioning to managing software and servers (December 20).'?",
    "option_A": "Elon Musk acquired Twitter for $44 billion.",
    "option_B": "The information provided is insufficient to determine the cause.",
    "option_C": "Elon Musk fired Twitter CEO Parag Agrawal, CFO Ned Segal, and general counsel Vijaya Gadde.",
    "option_D": "Elon Musk to acquire Twitter for $44 billion",
    "golden_answer": "A,C,D"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 6,
    "uuid": "4aa44e20-7843-442d-8599-9e9b1f6f8c00",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'Trump sweeps swing states: Trump wins in seven swing states, including Arizona (November 9, 2024)'?",
    "option_A": "Republicans used anti-trans hate to move people to the polls",
    "option_B": "Donald Trump elected president after winning Wisconsin and securing over 270 electoral votes.",
    "option_C": "Donald Trump was found guilty on 34 felony charges in New York.",
    "option_D": "The information provided is insufficient to determine the cause.",
    "golden_answer": "A,B"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 6,
    "uuid": "40d041a3-9f27-48ca-919d-f452c594e079",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'Donald Trump won the popular vote by approximately four million votes.'?",
    "option_A": "Donald Trump elected president after winning Wisconsin and securing over 270 electoral votes.",
    "option_B": "The information provided is insufficient to determine the cause.",
    "option_C": "Republicans used anti-trans hate to move people to the polls",
    "option_D": "Trump sweeps swing states: Trump wins in seven swing states, including Arizona (November 9, 2024)",
    "golden_answer": "A,C,D"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 6,
    "uuid": "2108bc2b-ff5f-47a6-9de1-1a2a487dff4c",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'Panelists analyzed potential limits on Trump's agenda and power, even with Republican control of Congress.'?",
    "option_A": "Johns Hopkins held a virtual event 'Insights and Impacts: Post-Election Debrief' on Nov. 7 to discuss the election's effects.",
    "option_B": "Donald Trump elected president after winning Wisconsin and securing over 270 electoral votes.",
    "option_C": "The information provided is insufficient to determine the cause.",
    "option_D": "Panelists discussed factors influencing the election, including polarization, economic disconnect, Trump's voter appeal, and information inconsistencies.",
    "golden_answer": "A,B"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 6,
    "uuid": "c92ae7e7-d455-4c8c-b672-81ff2d6e3b36",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'Concerns raised about the executive branch influencing future elections'?",
    "option_A": "Donald Trump won the popular vote by approximately four million votes.",
    "option_B": "Panelists discussed factors influencing the election, including polarization, economic disconnect, Trump's voter appeal, and information inconsistencies.",
    "option_C": "Donald Trump elected president after winning Wisconsin and securing over 270 electoral votes.",
    "option_D": "Trump sweeps swing states: Trump wins in seven swing states, including Arizona (November 9, 2024)",
    "golden_answer": "B,C,D"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 7,
    "uuid": "4cff1fa0-cedd-4eaf-8a69-07a6fac37f59",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'Impeachment Vote: Lawmakers voted on a motion to impeach President Yoon Suk Yeol; the motion failed.'?",
    "option_A": "Martial-law command suspended the legislature and controlled the media.",
    "option_B": "Performance: Baek Jae Gil performed his adapted anthem 'Impeachment is the answer' outside the National Assembly after Yoon's declaration of martial law.",
    "option_C": "Lawmakers overturned President Yoon's martial law declaration after tussling with troops to enter the National Assembly.",
    "option_D": "Yoon declared martial law on December 3, triggering protests.",
    "golden_answer": "A,C,D"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 7,
    "uuid": "08f72f4c-1dad-4385-9d20-6e5108c205d4",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'South Korean parliament impeached President Yoon Suk Yeol following his martial law attempt.'?",
    "option_A": "Performance: Baek Jae Gil performed his adapted anthem 'Impeachment is the answer' outside the National Assembly after Yoon's declaration of martial law.",
    "option_B": "Martial-law command suspended the legislature and controlled the media.",
    "option_C": "The information provided is insufficient to determine the cause.",
    "option_D": "Yoon declared martial law on December 3, triggering protests.",
    "golden_answer": "B,D"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 7,
    "uuid": "d3b216f6-696d-4075-a0db-d5a73ba99b13",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'Yoon faces criminal investigations including insurrection charges, potentially leading to arrest.'?",
    "option_A": "Yoon declared martial law on December 3, triggering protests.",
    "option_B": "The information provided is insufficient to determine the cause.",
    "option_C": "Performance: Baek Jae Gil performed his adapted anthem 'Impeachment is the answer' outside the National Assembly after Yoon's declaration of martial law.",
    "option_D": "Martial-law command suspended the legislature and controlled the media.",
    "golden_answer": "A,D"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 8,
    "uuid": "b56a9105-c414-44ad-ab0e-c3d32b965628",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'Mandalay General Hospital stopped admitting patients due to being full and lacking power and water.'?",
    "option_A": "A magnitude 7.7 (or 7.9) earthquake struck central Myanmar, near Sagaing and Mandalay, on March 28, 2025, at approximately 06:20 UTC (12:50 LT/Yangon time).",
    "option_B": "The earthquake was caused by a rupture lasting a full minute.",
    "option_C": "A large aftershock, including a magnitude 6.4 temblor occurring 12 minutes later, followed the initial earthquake.",
    "option_D": "The information provided is insufficient to determine the cause.",
    "golden_answer": "A,B,C"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 8,
    "uuid": "7c6313f7-99b3-4af3-bbe8-cf3fe98c938d",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'A skyscraper under construction collapsed in Bangkok, Thailand, causing casualties and disruption of services.'?",
    "option_A": "A magnitude 7.7 (or 7.9) earthquake struck central Myanmar, near Sagaing and Mandalay, on March 28, 2025, at approximately 06:20 UTC (12:50 LT/Yangon time).",
    "option_B": "The information provided is insufficient to determine the cause.",
    "option_C": "The earthquake was caused by a rupture lasting a full minute.",
    "option_D": "Mandalay General Hospital stopped admitting patients due to being full and lacking power and water.",
    "golden_answer": "A,C"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 8,
    "uuid": "887966e6-1c97-429f-bd7b-1db622ec6d02",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event '144 people were killed and 732 injured in Myanmar initially.'?",
    "option_A": "A magnitude 7.7 (or 7.9) earthquake struck central Myanmar, near Sagaing and Mandalay, on March 28, 2025, at approximately 06:20 UTC (12:50 LT/Yangon time).",
    "option_B": "The earthquake was caused by a rupture lasting a full minute.",
    "option_C": "A skyscraper under construction collapsed in Bangkok, Thailand, causing casualties and disruption of services.",
    "option_D": "Buildings collapsed and infrastructure was damaged in multiple locations in Myanmar, including Mandalay, Naypyidaw, and Sagaing Township.",
    "golden_answer": "A,B,D"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 8,
    "uuid": "4a0b37a5-97ef-48eb-811d-7449c3039b6a",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'Myanmar declared a state of emergency in six quake-affected areas.'?",
    "option_A": "The information provided is insufficient to determine the cause.",
    "option_B": "A magnitude 7.7 (or 7.9) earthquake struck central Myanmar, near Sagaing and Mandalay, on March 28, 2025, at approximately 06:20 UTC (12:50 LT/Yangon time).",
    "option_C": "A skyscraper under construction collapsed in Bangkok, Thailand, causing casualties and disruption of services.",
    "option_D": "The earthquake was caused by a rupture lasting a full minute.",
    "golden_answer": "B,D"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 8,
    "uuid": "4bee748f-571a-4da6-89ce-c7d310a7d2be",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'Myanmar's military government requested international humanitarian aid.'?",
    "option_A": "Buildings collapsed and infrastructure was damaged in multiple locations in Myanmar, including Mandalay, Naypyidaw, and Sagaing Township.",
    "option_B": "Mandalay General Hospital stopped admitting patients due to being full and lacking power and water.",
    "option_C": "A magnitude 7.7 (or 7.9) earthquake struck central Myanmar, near Sagaing and Mandalay, on March 28, 2025, at approximately 06:20 UTC (12:50 LT/Yangon time).",
    "option_D": "The information provided is insufficient to determine the cause.",
    "golden_answer": "A,B,C"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 8,
    "uuid": "6bbace13-5adf-4015-bf80-be029cebcac0",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'The UN began mobilizing aid for Myanmar.'?",
    "option_A": "A magnitude 7.7 (or 7.9) earthquake struck central Myanmar, near Sagaing and Mandalay, on March 28, 2025, at approximately 06:20 UTC (12:50 LT/Yangon time).",
    "option_B": "The information provided is insufficient to determine the cause.",
    "option_C": "The earthquake was caused by a rupture lasting a full minute.",
    "option_D": "A large aftershock, including a magnitude 6.4 temblor occurring 12 minutes later, followed the initial earthquake.",
    "golden_answer": "A,D"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 8,
    "uuid": "9b8c4d61-bbf9-4004-bf70-604be223ad95",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'Death toll rose to 4,390 in Myanmar and 36 in Thailand by April 3, following the earthquake on March 28, 2025.'?",
    "option_A": "Myanmar's military government requested international humanitarian aid.",
    "option_B": "A magnitude 7.7 (or 7.9) earthquake struck central Myanmar, near Sagaing and Mandalay, on March 28, 2025, at approximately 06:20 UTC (12:50 LT/Yangon time).",
    "option_C": "The earthquake was caused by a rupture lasting a full minute.",
    "option_D": "The information provided is insufficient to determine the cause.",
    "golden_answer": "B,C"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 9,
    "uuid": "f23cc014-b4e3-4ce6-a86c-f3ee9927201d",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'DOGE plans for executives to perform six-month voluntary stints inside the federal government, working 80-hour weeks without pay.'?",
    "option_A": "The information provided is insufficient to determine the cause.",
    "option_B": "The Department of Government Efficiency (DOGE) is established on the eve of President Trump's presidency, with Elon Musk and Vivek Ramaswamy appointed as its co-leaders.",
    "option_C": "DOGE begins recruiting over 50 staffers, aiming for 100 by Trump's inauguration.",
    "option_D": "The United States Digital Service is taken over and rebranded as United States DOGE Service.",
    "golden_answer": "B,C,D"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 9,
    "uuid": "df954136-5cc8-4e6e-8a6d-a908d0832177",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'Steve Davis, Emil Michael, Katie Miller, and Bill McGinley are appointed to leadership roles within DOGE.'?",
    "option_A": "The Department of Government Efficiency (DOGE) is established on the eve of President Trump's presidency, with Elon Musk and Vivek Ramaswamy appointed as its co-leaders.",
    "option_B": "DOGE begins recruiting over 50 staffers, aiming for 100 by Trump's inauguration.",
    "option_C": "The United States Digital Service is taken over and rebranded as United States DOGE Service.",
    "option_D": "The information provided is insufficient to determine the cause.",
    "golden_answer": "A,B,C"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 9,
    "uuid": "ff8efa25-c475-484f-a446-22bd3e19e8f6",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'Treasury Department's top civil servant, David Lebryk, resigns after DOGE officials inquire about stopping federal payments.'?",
    "option_A": "The United States Digital Service is taken over and rebranded as United States DOGE Service.",
    "option_B": "The Department of Government Efficiency (DOGE) is established on the eve of President Trump's presidency, with Elon Musk and Vivek Ramaswamy appointed as its co-leaders.",
    "option_C": "DOGE begins recruiting over 50 staffers, aiming for 100 by Trump's inauguration.",
    "option_D": "The information provided is insufficient to determine the cause.",
    "golden_answer": "A,B,C"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 9,
    "uuid": "737de92c-5a0d-4376-a390-934128efbb17",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'President Trump suggests federal workers who do not return to offices by a deadline will be fired.'?",
    "option_A": "The United States Digital Service is taken over and rebranded as United States DOGE Service.",
    "option_B": "DOGE begins recruiting over 50 staffers, aiming for 100 by Trump's inauguration.",
    "option_C": "The information provided is insufficient to determine the cause.",
    "option_D": "The Department of Government Efficiency (DOGE) is established on the eve of President Trump's presidency, with Elon Musk and Vivek Ramaswamy appointed as its co-leaders.",
    "golden_answer": "A,B,D"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 10,
    "uuid": "4c54db29-4b0a-4708-82bd-e713b52dfb7a",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'Navarro confirmed the planned Canadian tariff increase was canceled.'?",
    "option_A": "Doug Ford paused a surcharge (retaliation to US tariffs) after discussions.",
    "option_B": "Trump previously imposed tariffs on imported steel, aluminum, and from China, angering allies like Australia.",
    "option_C": "Trump planned to raise tariffs on Canadian steel and aluminum to 50%.",
    "option_D": "The information provided is insufficient to determine the cause.",
    "golden_answer": "A,B,C"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 10,
    "uuid": "afa71ddc-f5db-421c-95bd-44bd22f66cc8",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'China, Canada, and Mexico imposed retaliatory tariffs in response to Trump's tariffs.'?",
    "option_A": "The information provided is insufficient to determine the cause.",
    "option_B": "Trump previously imposed tariffs on imported steel, aluminum, and from China, angering allies like Australia.",
    "option_C": "Trump planned to raise tariffs on Canadian steel and aluminum to 50%.",
    "option_D": "The U.S. Embassy in China's Weibo account was flooded with angry comments expressing disappointment with U.S. policies.",
    "golden_answer": "B,C"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 10,
    "uuid": "b1ca4cb7-42e7-4888-b198-6e214183832b",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'President Trump announced new widespread tariffs, planning imposition on April 2.'?",
    "option_A": "The information provided is insufficient to determine the cause.",
    "option_B": "Trump previously imposed tariffs on imported steel, aluminum, and from China, angering allies like Australia.",
    "option_C": "Navarro confirmed the planned Canadian tariff increase was canceled.",
    "option_D": "Trump planned to raise tariffs on Canadian steel and aluminum to 50%.",
    "golden_answer": "B,D"
  },
  {
    "topic_id": 10,
    "uuid": "1b674725-b9df-47ad-b7a9-e2a3222de365",
    "question": "Which of the following options are the causes of the event 'Global stock markets declined following the widespread tariff announcements.'?",
    "option_A": "Navarro confirmed the planned Canadian tariff increase was canceled.",
    "option_B": "Doug Ford paused a surcharge (retaliation to US tariffs) after discussions.",
    "option_C": "Trump planned to raise tariffs on Canadian steel and aluminum to 50%.",
    "option_D": "Trump previously imposed tariffs on imported steel, aluminum, and from China, angering allies like Australia.",
    "golden_answer": "A,C,D"
  }
]